This is http://www.softwarepassion.com/deploy-your-java-application-with-izpack-installer/ a short tutorial on how to create simple IzPack based installation solution on windows platform with all standard features like: desktop shortcut, start menu item shortcut, copying libraries, folders, documentation into one of the ProgramFiles folder on the windows machine.
 
1. First download and install IzPack itself from: izpack website

2. Prepare the application you want to make installable. We end up with SomeApp.jar file. 
Navigate to the desktop module and execute the following command:

mvn assembly:assembly

This will create “jar spellbook-version-jar-with-dependencies.jar”.

3. Now, once we have all the main ingredients (our application and installer) we need to connect it together. Create the folder anywhere on your machine, and call it for example ’softwarepassion’.

4. Put your jar file into the ’softwarepassion’ catalog.

5. Now we need to add some native libraries for Izpack to be able to add windows shortcuts on the desktop and start menu. Create ‘bin’ folder under the ’softwarepassion’ folder and copy whole ‘native’ content found in your izpack installation into the ‘bin’ folder of your root ’softwarepassion’ catalog.
You can find the native folder inside your IzPack installation directory, normally under: ‘C:\Program Files\IzPack\bin’

6. Create your application icon file and add it to your ’softwarepasison’ catalog. I call mine ‘exe.ico’.

7. Now comes the hardest part to get initially but after you build your first installer it all gets clear and easy 
We need to prepare two separate xml files: one called ‘install.xml’ and another one called ’shortcutSpec.xml’. 
Shortcuts> INF/MANIFEST.MF > http://www.herongyang.com/Java-Tools/jar-Add-Manifest-to-JAR-Files.html 

8. Example installation script contains both Readme.txt and Licence.txt which you can add to your ’softwarepassion’ folder.
9. Once you have it all in one place, you should have a structure like in the following screenshot:
 
10. Now assuming that your ’softwarepassion’ folder has been placed directly on the c: drive, execute the following command:
C:\Program Files\IzPack\bin>compile c:\softwarepassion\install.xml -b c:\softwarepassion
Assuming that IzPack itself was installed at: C:\Program Files\IzPack
This will produce install.jar file which is your installer.

11. If you don’t want your end users to click on the ‘jar’ file as not everybody knows they can do that, you can add executable wrappers for Windows and Mac.
Windows > http://www.javalobby.org/articles/izpack/ 

12. Database >http://izpack.org/community/berlios-lists-archives/izpack-users/2006-September/000874.html 
Solution java > http://www.trustice.com/java/tar/ and http://www.kohsuke.org/bzip2/ 
Like this http://www.java2s.com/Tutorial/Java/0180__File/UgzipusingGZIPInputStream.htm and this http://stackoverflow.com/questions/938958/how-should-i-extract-compressed-folders-in-java 

Linux >http://marc.info/?l=linux-java&m=94631165025901&w=2  


modal progress dialog java
