============ Spellbook Dictionary ============ 

Spellbook is an platform-independent dictionary written in Java. 

Spellbook features stuff like:
 * exams
 * word study module 
 * spell checking module
 * educational games
 * clipboard integration 

Spellbook is free software developed jointly by Drow Ltd. and a
community of independent developers. The current version can be
obtained from http://code.google.com/p/spellbook-dictionary

Spellbook is always looking for people willing to join and contribute
to the project. If you are one of them do not hesitate to contact the
current project maintainer.
